Andrea Renee Rechtfertig califia\_10@yahoo.com P.O Box 853, Seymour, MO 65746 (417) 293-3252

#### **Objective Overview**

Extensive experience teaching Microsoft Office Suites, ESL, Spanish, Latin, and reading & writing to many different age groups as a certified teacher, and additional experience in pedagogy & curriculum development, as well as in proofreading and technical writing.

#### **Education & Certification**

Missouri State University	West Plains, MO
Wilsouit State Chive Sity	W CSt 1 Iams, 1410

Associates of Arts in General Studies May 1999

Missouri State University Springfield, MO

Bachelor of Science in Spanish; minor in TOEFL

December 2002

University of Arkansas Fayetteville, AR

Language teaching courses 2012

Graduate level foreign language grammar classes

Graduate level, foreign language pedagogy and Research.

American Board & Initial Professional Certificate

American Board

Certified to teach Elementary Education in Missouri March 15, 2018

#### **Related Work Experience**

### Music and ESL Teacher K-5<sup>th</sup> Grades

Seymour, Mo 2019-Current

- Implement professional music software for Choir (i.e., MuseScore).
- Created digital learning games about music.
- Successful choir and instrument ensembles through my student-centered lessons.

## Reading specialist and ESL teacher Seymour Public School

Seymour, MO 2018-2019

- Implement both synthetic/explicit as well as analytic/implicit phonics according to a students individualized reading needs.
- Designed group reading lessons for English as a second language.
- Differentiated lesson plan and goals for each student.
- Assessed and created reading goals and strategies for students in 1<sup>st</sup>-5<sup>th</sup> grade.
- Created effective interactive and engaging instructions through the use of technology.
- Implemented Bloom's hierarchy of learning to develop higher levels of thought processes in reading.
- Taught English as a second language using a variety of methods, such as TPRS information and gap.
- Maintained consistent routines and high-expectations.

### Para-professional/Tutor Logan Rogersville Elementary

Rogersville, MO

2014-2018

- Specialized in: reading, writing, and math.
- Implemented communicative methods for special needs such as sign language and PEKS picture exchange.
- Facilitated communication devices that maximized effective communication for students with verbal needs.
- Modified and/or created lessons.

## Student UARK-University of Arkansas

Fayetteville, AR 2013-2014

Teacher enrichment courses in foreign language pedagogy and curriculum design.

- Designed and published Interactive Spanish game on power point to TPT store.
- Learned and implemented current as well as former teaching methods and approaches for teaching a foreign language.
- Advanced Spanish grammar class for teachers.

## Teacher OCA-Spanish, Latin, Writing, Reading & Computers

West Plains, MO 2006-2012

- Taught Level I & II in Spanish for four years.
- Implemented the TPRS method (i.e., total physical response through reading and story-telling).
- Also, implemented explicit grammar lessons and ultimately aimed for communicative as well as grammatical competence as the primary goal.
- Taught elementary through high school Latin for four years.
- In Latin, the classical approach was the teaching method that I used. In the classical approach, the Latin grammar, unlike my Spanish classes, is taught explicitly rather than communicatively.
- In my creative writing class, I taught: descriptive, narrative, informative, persuasive, and opinion essays. I also taught: compare & contrast essays, timed essays, and journalism.
- In my science thinking class, we discussed worldviews and presuppositions followed by methodical and varied science topics.
- In my computer class, I taught speed-typing, as well as the Microsoft Essentials subcomponents, which include: Word, Excel, Power Point, and Database.
- I also incorporated Movie Maker and
- Adobe Photoshop.

## Private Tutor Latin & English as a Second Language

Home, USA 2010-2012

#### English as a second language

- Taught English as a second language to elementary age Spanish speaking student every day after school.
- Implemented the TPRS method.
- Created Power Points and Lesson Plans.
- Created Quizzes.

• Focused on improving students' grammar, comprehension, and speaking skills.

#### Latin

- Helped struggling students to maximize their comprehension and approach with the Latin, which resulted in improved grades and better understanding in class.
- Implemented the Classical Approach.
- Grammar and Reading.
- Word and Sentence diagramming.

## Proofreader & Editor The PEN (Proofreaders & Editors Network)

Remote 2006

- Online freelance proofreader & prospective editor.
- Completed various online courses through the network.
- Implemented this valuable knowledge as an English, writing, and grammar instructor.

## Teacher Baku International School, Azerbaijan.

Baku, Azerbaijan 2004-2005

- Substitute elementary teacher:
- Prepared and conducted effective lessons for the six-year-old class.
- Maintained positive interaction with parents.
- Maintained students' grades & homework records.

#### **ESL Teacher:**

- Constructed and implemented guided controlled exercises.
- Created exercises dealing with comprehension of inferences.
- Taught with a content-based curriculum, and implemented various teaching strategies.

# **Teacher Community Montessori School**

Reston Virginia 2003-2004

- Implemented techniques known as the *Whole Child Approach* which resembled guidance rather than direct teaching for children in their early childhood.
- Assisted and instructed about 12 preschool age children.

## Student Teacher Missouri State University

Springfield, MO June-Nov. 2002

- As a student teacher, I assisted with preparations of numerous lesson plans.
- Implemented and designed active listening and speaking exercises.
- Instructed and conducted class with additional mentoring through my professor.